

Annemarie Sheridan

SEEKING FULL TIME REMOTE POSITION AT TECHNOVATION TO CONTRIBUTE INSPIRATION

SKILLS

ABOUT ME

Greetings fellow inspirers in tech! I am an enthusiastic tech professional with a recent history as a PLTW Master App Creator Teacher for 2 years & completing an intense coding program learning skills such as HTML, CSS, Javascript, Node.js, jQuery, Bootstrap, MySQL, MongoDB, Express.js, and React.js. After working more than 10 years in education including teaching overseas, I have transitioned into the world of innovation to expand my strengths in STEM and surround myself with other tech motivated creatives, inventors and fun nerds!

EDUCATION

Completion of Full Stack Development
UNIVERSITY OF ARIZONA
CODING BOOTCAMP (2023)

PLTW App Creator Cert. 2021

100 Hour TESOL Certificate
ITTT (2010)

Bachelor of Arts: Graphic Design URSULINE COLLEGE (2008)

CONTACT

971-732-2441

atsheridan38@gmail.com

Las Vegas, Nevada





Coding Skills Specific Communication and Leadership







Diverse Experiences Expanding Empathy



Creative Problem Solver

EXPERIENCE

PLTW App Creator Master Teacher (2021-present)
MATER ACADEMY MOUNTAIN VISTA

- Teach beginner coding classes using MIT App Inventor & PLTW curriculum
- Achieved PLTW Master Teacher level in less than 1 year to train teachers
- Mentor students that participate in App Competitions
- Track record of growth for more than 50% of the class
- Utilize outsource curriculum to further excite my students about STEM.

Volunteer Educator Mentor (2022-present)
TECHNOVATION NONPROFIT

- Recruit and encourage underserved girl students to participate in the App Competition.
- Proactively <u>mentor</u> students in creative brainstorming and making an outline.
- Communicate with fellow mentors or support coordinators to stay updated with any questions or concerns.



AAAAA

EXPERIENCE

Library Technician / Ass. Teacher (2017-2021) PARADISE ELEMENTARY SCHOOL

- Improved students research and tech skills by 90%
- Assisted in tracking library data records to ensure accuracy by 90%
- Helped librarian in researching lesson plan materials and students' comprehension of assignments in class.
- Investigated and wrote reports of damaged tech equipment to maintain up to date maintenance by 90%

English Language Teacher / Facility Manager (2015-2016)

PRINCETON REVIEW KOREA

- Counseled non-native English speakers on English language fundamentals within cultural context of engaging in productive cross cultural interactions which increased awareness by 80%
- Taught lessons on diversity, cultural awareness in business and tolerance that increased social skills by 90%
- Communicated weekly reports on students attendance in the facility
- Advised participants during cross cultural misunderstandings, successfully de-escalating communication barriers and conflicts leveraging proven crosscultural communications techniques.

English Language Teacher (2014-2015) YEONGJU ENGLISH CENTER

- Taught interactive and hands-on English lessons utilizing Power Point presentations.
- Leveraged active listening skills and cultural understanding to assess, defuse, and mediate intercultural misunderstandings.

Toastmasters International | 2010 - 2012

English Language Teacher/Curriculum Designer GURI GIRLS MIDDLE SCHOOL

- Taught English classes about interesting topics such as racial and cultural bias, diversity, and life lessons.
- Introduced and utilized innovative curriculum concepts within the English Department which was implemented in the classroom which enhanced students attention by 80%.
- Taught a weekly Adult English
 Language Discussion class which led to
 growth by 80%
- Taught English classes to an economically diverse population including first-generation students of 20%.

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

Youth Leadership Program Manager (2012) TOASTMASTERS INTERNATIONAL

- Counseled 6 student leaders in an 8-week program on personal development, goal attainment, group accountability emphasizing self-awareness and conflict resolution.
- Improved students' public speaking, selfawareness, friendship skills and confidence by 100%.
- Provided high-quality support through training involving event planning skills such as scheduling, venue research, budgeting, and agenda planning.